Guide to the McKinney Family Papers, 1823-1964
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VIII. Ethelyn McKinney
  - Sketches of Parisian fashion, [1899?] (Folder 15.10)
  - Songbook for Phi Kappa Psi, 1898 or 1899 (Folder 15.11)
  - Envelope with notes about old English words, 1898 or 1899 (Folder 15.12)
  - Misc: invitation, opera program, Dixie Room menu, theatre mask picture, [1898-1899?] (Folder 15.13)
  - Notes on Western trip, 1898 or 1899 (Folder 15.14)
  - Various small notes, [1898-1899?] (Folder 15.15)
  - Various greeting cards to Ethelyn from friends and family, [1898or 1899?] (Folder 15.16)
  - Subscription fee from College Settlements Association, [1900?] (Folder 15.17)
  - Receipt from Cesira Bencini and Vedova Baldini's Antique Lace Shop [Florence], 1 May 1900 (Folder 15.18)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [Bavaria], 10 June 1900 (Folder 15.19)
  - Receipts from L. Garrique Tailor for Women, 30 June 1900 (Folder 15.20)
  - Receipt from Emilie Mouchinnet's Rubes and Manteaux [Paris], 27 July 1900 (Folder 15.20)
  - Contribution card for Smith College Alumni Committee, 26 Aug 1901 (Folder 15.21)
  - Letter from L. Clark Seeyle, President of Smith re: endowments, 18 July 1901 (Folder 15.21)
  - Ephemera, undated (Folder 15.22)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Lena [Hotel Marlton, New York], 31 Dec 1901 (Folder 15.23)
  - Extract from letter, 1 Feb 1902 (Folder 15.24)
  - "A Chinese Bottle's Tale" from L.M.W. (Lena Weinstein), 25 Dec 1902 (Folder 15.25)
  - Valentine to Ethelyn signed L. (Lena), 14 Feb 1903 (Folder 15.26)
  - Ethelyn McKinney's Passport No. 68879, 14 Apr 1903 (Folder 15.27)
  - Letter to Glenn and family from Ethelyn [S.S. Minnehana], 16-24 May 1903 (Folder 15.28)
  - Letters to Glenn and family from Ethelyn [De Keyer's Royal Hotel, London], 1 and 7 June 1903; (2) (Folder 15.29)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Hotel De La Paix, Anvers], 14 June 1903 (Folder 15.30)
  - Letters to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [Amsterdam and Koln], 17 and 20 June 1903; (2) (Folder 15.31)
  - Notes re: Summer 1903 (Folder 15.32)
  - Letter to (Annette?) from Ethelyn [Berliner Hotel Gesellschaft], 27 June 1903 (Folder 15.33)
  - Letters to Grandmother Ford and J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Hotel d'Angelterre, St. Petersburg], 4-13 July 1903 (Folder 15.34)
  - Letter to Glenn and family from Ethelyn [On the Volga steamer "Field Marshall Grovorov"], 17 July 1903 (Folder 15.35)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [Vlasikavkow, Russia], 28 July 1903 (Folder 15.36)
  - Postcard to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Russia], 23 July 1903 (Folder 15.37)
  - Paper written in Russian, undated (Folder 15.37)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [On the steamer "Espero"- The Black Sea], 3 Aug 1903 (Folder 15.38)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [Grand Hotel De Londres, Constantinople], 11 Aug 1903 (Folder 15.39)
  - Letter to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [Athens, Greece], 21 Aug 1903 (Folder 15.40)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Brindisi, Italy], 31 Aug 1903 (Folder 15.41)
  - Letter to Annette from Ethelyn [Vienna, Austria], 12 Oct 1903 (Folder 15.42)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Florence, Italy], 20 Dec 1903 (Folder 15.43)
  - Collection of poems, 1903 (Folder 15.44)
  - Envelope from Compagnia Rotografica, 1903 (Folder 15.45)
  - Photos of Russia, 1903 (Folder 15.46)
  - Piece of Paper "Contents: Letter from my daughter Ida Ethelyn McKinney...", 1904 (Folder 15.47)
  - Letter to Grandmother from Ethelyn [France], 27 Mar 1904 (Folder 15.48)
  - Letter to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [Royal Hotel, Ronda], 13-15 Apr 1904 (Folder 15.49)
  - Letter to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [St. Sebastian], 1 May 1904 (Folder 15.50)
  - Letters to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [Paris], 18 and 26 May 1904; (2) (Folder 16.1)
  - Letter to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [Rugby, England], 18 June 1904 (Folder 16.2)
  - Telegram to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Rugby, England], 21 June 1904 (Folder 16.3)
  - Ephemera, 4 July 1904; 8 Mar 1904; undated (Folder 16.4)
  - Postcard to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [London], 8 July 1904 (Folder 16.5)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [London], 17 July 1904 (Folder 16.6)
  - Letter to Grandmother Ford from Ethelyn [London], 24 July 1904 (Folder 16.7)
  - Letter to Glenn and Annette from Ethelyn [London], 7 Aug 1904 (Folder 16.8)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Paris], 4 Sept 1904 (Folder 16.9)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn, [23 Sept 1904] (Folder 16.10)
  - Visiting card from Madame Belloc [England], 30 Oct 1904 (Folder 16.11)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [Canon Greenwell?] [Durham], 8 Nov 1904 (Folder 16.12)
  - Poem "With a Necklace" from L.M.W., 25 Dec 1904 (Folder 16.13)
  - Smith College Decennial Reunion '95, 20 June 1905 (Folder 16.14)
  - Poems, 20 June 1905 (Folder 16.15)
  - Postcard for L.M. Weinstein from Ethelyn, 31 July 1905 (Folder 16.16)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from W. Greenwell [Durham], 25 Dec 1905 (Folder 16.17)
  - Copy of an advertisement [Nikko, Japan], 1906-1907 (Folder 16.18)
  - Checks made out by Ethelyn McKinney, 1906-1907 (Folder 16.19)
  - Calendar for 1906 (Japanese) (Folder 16.20)
  - "The Daughter of Selena" song, 1906 (Folder 16.21)
  - "Early Italian Sculptors" by Lena M. Weinstein, 1900 (Folder 16.22)
  - Italian Sculptors (con't) "Florence", 1900 (Folder 16.23)
  - (con't) "The Middle Renaissance", 1900 (Folder 16.24)
  - Notes on Naples, Rome, etc., undated (Folder 16.25)
  - "Savonarola's Influence Upon the Art and Culture of Florence", 1901 (Folder 16.26)
  - Pamphlet Covers for "Six Talks on Art", [1900 or 1901?] (Folder 16.27)
  - Copy of letter to [E. Harvey?] from Ethelyn, 8 Apr 1906 (Folder 16.28)
  - Letter to G. F. McKinney from John A. Wendle [Riverside, Conn.], 22 June 1906 (Folder 16.29)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from G. F. McKinney [New York], 20 Aug 1906 (Folder 16.30)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [On board S.S. Ramses on the Nile], 23 Nov 1906 (Folder 16.31)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [On board S.S. Ramses on the Nile], 28 Nov 1906 (Folder 16.32)
  - Letters to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [Shepard's Hotel, Cairo], 4 Dec 1906; (2) (Folder 16.33)
  - Letter to William G. Tachau from Ethelyn [Cairo], 7 Dec 1906 (Folder 16.34)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [On the S.S. Peroia on the Red Sea] (Folder 16.35)
  - Copy of Edwin Arnold's poem "After Death in Arabia", undated (Folder 16.36)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Bombay, India], 25 Dec 1906 (Folder 16.37)
  - Letter to Annette from Ethelyn [Agra, India], 3 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.38)
  - Letter to "Heart" from Ethelyn [Darjeeling, India], 15 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.39)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William G. Tachau [New York], 20 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.40)
  - Envelope addressed to William G. Tachau from Ethelyn [Calcutta, India], 20 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.41)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [Aboard S.S. Palitana in the Bay of Bengal], 20 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.42)
  - Letter to G. F. McKinney from Ethelyn [On board S.S. Japan in the Irrawaddy River, Burma], 24 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.43)
  - Letter to William G. Tachau from Ethelyn [On board S.S. Japan in Burma], 24 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.44)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [On board S.S. Japan in Burma], 29 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.45)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William G. Tachau [New York], 31 Jan 1907 (Folder 16.46)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from William G. Tachau [New York], 10 Feb 1907 (Folder 16.47)
  - Letter to William G. Tachau from Ethelyn [Kandy, Ceylon], 13 Feb 1907 (Folder 16.48)
  - Verses by Phillips Brooks, undated (Folder 16.49)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [Nuwara Eliya, Ceylon], 14-15 Feb 1907 (Folder 16.50)
  - Cartoon cardboard cutout of William G. Tachau from Ethelyn, undated (Folder 16.51)
  - Photos of Ethelyn on her trip [Rangoon], undated (Folder 16.52)
  - Letter to Annette from Ethelyn [On S.S. Nalta from Colombo-Singapore], 26 Feb 1907 (Folder 16.53)
  - Letter to Glenn and Annette from Ethelyn, 27 Feb 1907 (Folder 16.54)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William G. Tachau, 4 Mar 1907? (Folder 16.55)
  - Letter from L. Eva Alden to friends re: introduction of Lena Weinstein and Ethelyn in Siam [Bangkok, Siam], undated (Folder 16.56)
  - Postcard to Grandma ford from Ethelyn [Java], 16 Mar 1907 (Folder 16.57)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [On steamer Van Goens to Singapore], 22 Mar 1907 (Folder 16.58)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [On board La Ville de la Ciotal en route to Hong Kong], 29 Mar 1907 (Folder 16.59)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [On board La Ville de la Ciotal en route to Hong Kong], 31 Mar 1907 (Folder 16.60)
  - Letter to G. F. McKinney from Ethelyn [Onboard S.S. China], 11 Apr 1907 (Folder 17.1)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn, 26 Apr 1907 (Folder 17.2)
  - List of people at the Mikado Hotel, undated (Folder 17.2)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn [Yamada, Ise, Japan], 30 Apr 1907 (Folder 17.3)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Miyanoshita, Sagami, Japan], undated (Folder 17.4)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [Miyanoshita, Sagami, Japan], 5 May 1901 (Folder 17.5)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Tokyo, Japan], 12 May 1907 (Folder 17.6)
  - Letter to Grandma Ford from Ethelyn, 25 May 1907 (Folder 17.7)
  - Photos of Japan, 25 May 1907; (2) (Folder 17.7)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn with letter to J. L. McKinney, 25 May 1907 (Folder 17.8)
  - Photo of Ethelyn, 25 May 1907 (Folder 17.8)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn with telegram and 3 photos, 29 May 1907 (Folder 17.9)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William G. Tachau, 30 May 1907 (Folder 17.10)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [Yokohama, Japan], 11 June 1907 (Folder 17.11)
  - Mementos from Japan, [1907?] (Folder 17.12)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn [S.S. America Maru], [25?] June 1907 (Folder 17.13)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Earl Harvey Lyall [New York], 27 June 1907 (Folder 17.14)
  - Postcards to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [San Francisco], 8 July 1907 and 2 Aug 1907; (2) (Folder 17.15)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [San Francisco], 1 Aug 1907 (Folder 17.16)
  - Notes on World Trip by Ethelyn, [1907 or 1908?] (Folder 17.17)
  - Ephemera, [1906 or 1907?] (Folder 17.18)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from (Lena Weinstein), 15 Aug 1907; 21 Aug 1907; 7 Sept 1907 (Folder 17.19)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Lena Weinstein, 8 and 10 Sept 1907 (Folder 17.20)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [envelope dated], 6 Feb 1908 (Folder 17.21)
  - Receipts from various florists and landscape architects, 9 Apr - Oct 1908 (Folder 17.22)
  - Receipts from various furniture importers, 18 Mar - June 1908 (Folder 17.23)
  - Wedding invitation from Mr. 7 Mrs. John Burkinshaw for their daughter Hilda Wynnefred, [10 June 1908?] (Folder 17.24)
  - Letter to Miss Weinstein from (Ethelyn), 14 June 1908 (Folder 17.25)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn, 19 June and July 1908 (Folder 17.26)
  - Greeting card from the Friends' General Conference [Winona Lake, Indiana], Aug 1908 (Folder 17.27)
  - Letters to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn, 5 and 20 Aug 1908; (2) (Folder 17.31)
  - Receipt from A.A. Vantine and Co. Importers [New York], 1 Sept 1908 (Folder 17.32)
  - Poem "Wood [illegible word]" By Beth Slater Whitson, 12 Sept 1908 (Folder 17.33)
  - Post card to Ethelyn from unidentified correspondent, 9 Oct 1908 (Folder 17.33)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Alfred Williams and Sons [Port Chester, NY], 20 Oct 1908 (Folder 17.34)
  - Letter, contract, and map re: construction of addition to Ethelyn McKinney's barn, 27 Oct 1907 (Folder 17.35)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 24 Jan 1909 (Folder 17.36)
  - Valentine to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 11 Feb 1909 (Folder 17.37)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from William N. Brockway Wholesale Carriage Builder forwarded to Ethelyn, 15 Feb 1909 (Folder 17.38)
  - Postal card to J. L. McKinney fro Ethelyn [New York], 27 Feb 1909 (Folder 17.39)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Anyan and Hadden Contractors, 12 Mar 1909 (Folder 17.40)
  - Bill from Hutchinson and Fitzgerald Plumbing, Tinning, and Heating, Apr 1909 (Folder 17.41)
  - Blueprint for house, [1909] (Folder 17.42)
  - Post card to Ethelyn from Annette [New York], 10 Apr 1909 (Folder 17.43)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Greenwich, Conn.], 30 July 1909 (Folder 17.44)
  - Receipt - Federal Brass and Bronze Company, 25 Aug 1909 (Folder 17.45)
  - Receipt - A.A. Vantine and Co. Importers, 1 Sept 1909 (Folder 17.45)
  - Letter to Lena Weinstein from Hero Nobata [Yokohama, Japan], 10 Oct 1909 (Folder 17.46)
  - Letter to family from Ethelyn, 31 Oct 1909 (Folder 17.47)
  - Receipt from Di Salvo Brothers [New York], 20 Nov 1909 (Folder 17.48)
  - Ephemera, [1908-1909?] (Folder 17.49)
  - Pamphlet on George Breed Zug's "Extended Course if Illustrated Lecture on the Italian Paintings of the Renaissance", [1908 or 1909?] (Folder 17.50)
  - Christmas quotes and 2 visiting cards, undated (Folder 18.1)
  - Poems from Admiral (illegible name) III, undated (Folder 18.2)
  - I. Brener Live Stock Business Card, undated (Folder 18.2)
  - Framed Photo of Japanese temple with plaid ribbon, undated (Folder 18.3)
  - Christmas trifles, undated; (3) (Folder 18.4)
  - Clippings re: Ethelyn McKinney losing valuable family pearls in the streets of New York, [Dec 1909] (Folder 18.5)
  - Letters to Ethelyn from the New York American "Want Ads", 28 Dec 1909 (Folder 18.6)
  - Check to the Pinkertons National Detective Agency and 2 business cards, 8 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.7)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Emmanuel B. Lewis [New York], 12 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.8)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Frank W. Padelford [Boston], 14 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.9)
  - Copy of letter to Frank W. Padelford from Ethelyn [New York], 15 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.10)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Emmanuel B. Lewis [New York], 16 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.11)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Frank W. Padelford [Boston, MA], 17 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.12)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from The New York Times Want Advertising Department [New York], 21 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.13)
  - Telegram to Ethelyn from Frank. W. Padelford/ Telegram from J. L. McKinney, 28 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.14)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Grace Padelford [Lynne, Mass.], [1910] (Folder 18.15)
  - Telegram to J. L. McKinney from G. F. McKinney, 29 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.16)
  - New York Times Clipping re: Ethelyn's recovered pearls, 30 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.17)
  - Letters to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 2 Feb 1910 (Folder 18.18)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from Mrs. F.W. Padelford [Berlin], 22 July [1910] (Folder 18.19)
  - Obituary for Jean Reynolds and letter to Reynolds family from Ethelyn, 26 Jan 1910 (Folder 18.20)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 19 Apr 1910 (Folder 18.21)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Charlotte B. Connor, 29 Apr and 6 May 1910 (Folder 18.22)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from C. B. Connor [New York], 5 June 1910 (Folder 18.23)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from C. B. Connor, 8 June 1910 (Folder 18.24)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 24 June 1910 (Folder 18.25)
  - Receipt from C.B. Brokaw Auto Co. [New York], 31 Aug 1910 (Folder 18.26)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William Tachau written on Lewis Frederick Pilcher Stationary, 30 Sept 1910 (Folder 18.27)
  - Letters to J. L. McKinney from George R. McKinney, 6, 14 and 16 Oct 1910; (3) (Folder 18.28)
  - Bill from New York Central and Hudson River Railroad; envelope addressed to J. L. McKinney, 18 Oct 1910; 20 Oct 1910 (Folder 18.29)
  - Christmas card from Hero Nobata [Yokohama, Japan], 25 Dec 1910 (Folder 18.30)
  - New Years Greeting to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn, 1 Jan 1911 (Folder 18.31)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from George R. McKinney [Warren, PA], 24 Jan 1911 (Folder 18.32)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from ? [Indiana], 19 Feb 1911 (Folder 18.33)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 20 Apr 1911 (Folder 18.34)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William Tachau [New York], 31 Aug 1911 (Folder 18.35)
  - Billing from Gotham Motor car Company [New York], 13 Sept 1911 (Folder 18.36)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Art Mandell [Oct 8, 1911], 8 Oct 1911 (Folder 18.37)
  - Receipt from the Gotham Motor Car Company [New York], 5 Dec 1911 (Folder 18.38)
  - Receipt from The Locomobile Company of America [Bridgeport, Conn.], 9 Apr 1912 (Folder 18.39)
  - Letter to Lena from her mother with a dried flower, [4 May 1912?] (Folder 18.40)
  - Letter to "Mame" from Ethelyn [Dublin, Ireland], 21-23 July 1913 (Folder 18.41)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Cork], 25 July 1912 (Folder 18.42)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Galway], 1 Aug 1912 (Folder 18.43)
  - Letters to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [Donegal], 20 Aug 1912 (Folder 18.44)
  - Valentine Cards, undated (Folder 18.45)
  - Miscellaneous: The Jean Webster Home Letters, undated (Folder 19.1)
  - Correspondence between G. F. McKinney and Emily Westwood Lewis, undated (Folder 19.1)
  - Correspondence between Lena Weinstein and Emily Westwood Lewis, undated (Folder 19.1)
  - The Pittsburgh Index article on the Automobile, undated (Folder 19.2)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn [New York], 9 Jan 1913 (Folder 19.3)
  - Recipe for Baked Apple Dumpling, undated (Folder 19.4)
  - Invitation from the Greenwich Society of Artists, 1 Nov 1913 (Folder 19.5)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Moy Gum? [New York], 21 Nov 1913 (Folder 19.6)
  - Program for "Dances" by Virginia Myers [Carnegie Lyceum, New York], 4 Dec 1913 (Folder 19.7)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [Ida Camtock, Dean of Smith College?] [Northampton, MA], 16 Dec 1913 (Folder 19.8)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena Weinstein from Ethel Meyers [On board R.M.S. Olympic], 4 June 1914 (Folder 19.9)
  - Article: "When Virginia Dances" from Vogue Magazine, 1 June 1914 (Folder 19.10)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena from Ethel Meyers [Paris], Summer 1914 (Folder 19.11)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn and Lena from Ethel, Jerome, and Virginia [Great Britain], 6 Aug 1914 (Folder 19.12)
  - Car order form from The Locomobile Company of America, 20 July 1915 (Folder 19.13)
  - Letter to "Friends" from (Ethelyn?) [Greenwich, Conn.], undated (Folder 19.14)
  - Postcards addressed to Ethelyn, Jan1914 - Oct 1915 (Folder 19.15)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [?] [Florence], 10 Jan 1915 (Folder 19.16)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena from C.B. Connor [New York], 20 Jan 1916 (Folder 19.17)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena from C.B. Connor [New York], 22 Apr 1916 (Folder 19.18)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Elizabeth L. Howe [Princeton, NJ], [10 June 1916?] (Folder 19.19)
  - Page of an engagement calendar with nothing written on it, 26 Sept 1916 (Folder 19.20)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from William Tachau, [15 Aug 1916?] (Folder 19.21)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from The Women's University Club [New York], 18 July 1917 (Folder 19.22)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena from C.B. Connor, 2 Oct 1917 (Folder 19.23)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from sister Marie Elise [New York], 19 Dec 1917 (Folder 19.24)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Hero Nobata [Yokahama, Japan], 28 Oct 1918 (Folder 19.25)
  - Letter to Ethelyn McKinney from Ethel Myers [Carmel, NY], Sept 1918 (Folder 19.26)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from James McKinney [Titusville, PA], 30 Jan 1918 (Folder 19.27)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [Adda Andreves?] [Italy], 30 Jan 1918 (Folder 19.28)
  - Christmas prayer cards, undated (Folder 19.29)
  - Letter to Ethelyn and Lena from C.B. Connor, Easter 1918 (Folder 19.30)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [Neemis Molter?], 1918 (Folder 19.31)
  - Menu from Plats du Jour [New York], 9 Apr 1918 (Folder 19.32)
  - Letter to L.M. Weinstein from Hilda W. Fitzwilliams [Sussex], 20 Aug 1918 (Folder 19.33)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from W.S. Richardson [New York], 13 Jan 1919 (Folder 19.34)
  - Letter to Lena from her mother [Terre Haute, Indiana], 19 Jan 1919 (Folder 19.35)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from James McKinney [Titusville, PA], 1 Feb 1919 (Folder 19.36)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from (Adda Andreves?) [Florence], 20 Jan 1919 (Folder 19.37)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from George C. Vincent (President of the Rockefeller Foundation) [New York], 24 Feb 1919 (Folder 19.38)
  - Invitation from the Greenwich Society of Artists, 17 May 1919 (Folder 19.39)
  - Notes by Ethelyn McKinney, undated (Folder 19.40)
  - Poems, Frames done by Jean, Nov 1920 (Folder 19.41)
  - Postcard to Ethelyn from [Adda Andreves?], 11 Apr 1924 (Folder 19.42)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Count Ilya Tolstoy, 5 Dec 1924 (Folder 19.43)
  - Christmas Card from Lena, undated (Folder 19.44)
  - Poem from "Fifty-Ave. Poems" by Mary Webb, undated (Folder 19.45)
  - New York Times Clipping: "Sir Edward Seymour Gets Duchy of Somerset...", 26 Mar 1925 (Folder 19.46)
  - Christmas poem to "Mistress" (Ethelyn?) from [Togo Boy?], 25 Dec 1925 (Folder 19.47)
  - Advertisement from the U.S. Oxygen Company, undated (Folder 19.48)
  - Poem: "Mammy" by Ethelyn McKinney, June 1926 (Folder 19.49)
  - Poem: "A Farewell Song of White Clouds" by Li Po, copied, 18 Mar 1932 (Folder 19.50)
  - A little rhyme called Yuwanda from a book about Gloops, undated (Folder 19.51)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from [William Wallace Quinn?] [New York], 5 July [1928?] (Folder 19.52)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Elizabeth Westwood [New York], undated (Folder 19.53)
  - Valentine card and envelope, 1927 (Folder 19.54)
  - Letter to Lena from her mother, July 1927 (Folder 19.55)
  - Poems by Ethelyn McKinney, 17 July 1928 (Folder 20.1)
  - Untitled poem by Ethelyn McKinney. "It is not the end...", undated (Folder 20.2)
  - Poems by Ethelyn McKinney, "The Question" and "To You", 10 Sept 1928 (Folder 20.3)
  - Certificate announcing Ethelyn's appointment as an Elector of the Town of Greenwich, Conn., 31 Aug 1929 (Folder 20.4)
  - Ephemera, undated (Folder 20.5)
  - Unaddressed birthday card, undated (Folder 20.6)
  - Poem: "First Flight" by Robert P. Tristam Coffin, undated (Folder 20.7)
  - Ephemera, 1930-1939 (Folder 20.8)
  - Poem [by Ethelyn?] "There was a child...", undated (Folder 20.9)
  - Poem by Lena Weinstein, undated (Folder 20.10)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Jane Eraus, 18 Mar 1929 (Folder 20.11)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Billy (William Tachau), 23 Mar 1929 (Folder 20.12)
  - Letter to Ethelyn form Cora, [1929] (Folder 20.13)
  - Telegram to Ethelyn from Blanch Ferry Hooker [New York], 18 Mar 1929 (Folder 20.14)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Louise Zwachtman of the Mystery Club, 18 Apr 1929 (Folder 20.15)
  - Letter to "Ethelyn and Cloud" and postcard from Major Fitzwilliams, 3 Dec 1931 (Folder 20.16)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Fredric H. Kent, Treasurer of Bennington College, 22 June 1932 (Folder 20.17)
  - Invitation to ground breaking ceremony for Bennington College, 16 Aug 1931 (Folder 20.18)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Mary MacColl [Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, NY], 29 July 1933 (Folder 20.19)
  - Letter to Mary MacColl from Ethelyn [Greenwich, Conn.], [28 July] 1933 (Folder 20.20)
  - Ethelyn's1934Income Tax Return (Folder 20.21)
  - Telegram to Ethelyn from Clarence? [Hot Springs, AZ], 10 Mar 1934 (Folder 20.22)
  - List of active members in the Mystery Club, undated (Folder 20.23)
  - Poem: "Release" by Ethelyn McKinney, 15 Feb 1934 (Folder 20.24)
  - Invitation, "Miss McKinney at Home", 31 May [1934?] (Folder 20.25)
  - Pages from The New Yorker, 16 and 30 Mar 1935 (Folder 20.26)
  - Article from the International Press News Service re: Quill Jones, undated (Folder 20.27)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Quill Jones, 1917 (Folder 20.28)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from Quill Jones in Japan, 16 Sept 1917; undated; (2) (Folder 20.29)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from Hero Nobata [Yokohama, Japan], 26 Sept 1917 (Folder 20.30)
  - Clipping re: Quill Jones, undated (Folder 20.31)
  - Clipping re: Quill Jones's death, 27 July 1954 (Folder 20.32)